<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computational Design on Arman Wu&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://armanwu.github.io/categories/computational-design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Computational Design on Arman Wu&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 16:01:46 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://armanwu.github.io/categories/computational-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Intuition and Algorithm in Harmony: Architects in the Age of Artificial Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://armanwu.github.io/posts/2024/09/intuition-and-algorithm-in-harmony-architects-in-the-age-of-artificial-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 16:01:46 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://armanwu.github.io/posts/2024/09/intuition-and-algorithm-in-harmony-architects-in-the-age-of-artificial-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://armanwu.github.io/img/very_simple_expressive_fragmented_and_distorted_geometr.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sketch&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As artificial intelligence (AI) continues to influence various industries, including architecture, it raises important questions: How can the intuitive intelligence built over years of experience be combined with algorithmic logic? Both have powerful roles, and when united, they can create a new harmony in the world of architecture. However, to achieve this balance, architects need to understand how to work with AI while maintaining the essence of their intuition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discovering Harmony in Architecture with Generative Design</title>
      <link>https://armanwu.github.io/posts/2023/06/discovering-harmony-in-architecture-with-generative-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 20:44:46 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://armanwu.github.io/posts/2023/06/discovering-harmony-in-architecture-with-generative-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the complex world of architecture, generative design has emerged, opening doors to thousands of possibilities for harmonious and aesthetic designs. The collaboration between humans and computers gives rise to surprising solutions, unearthing new ideas with unlimited freedom.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Generative design involves the consideration of complex factors, including spatial layout, lighting, and energy efficiency. In this remarkable process, algorithms can be programmed to optimize designs based on specific criteria, creating unexpected harmony in the combination of variables. A symbiosis occurs between human intelligence and computational power, where architects provide insights and intuition, while generative design translates those ideas into reality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Thinking in Architectural Design Process</title>
      <link>https://armanwu.github.io/posts/2022/01/computational-thinking-in-architectural-design-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 21:44:46 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://armanwu.github.io/posts/2022/01/computational-thinking-in-architectural-design-process/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The use of computers in the field of architectural design initially only involved digitizing tasks that were traditionally done manually. Computer-based modeling or drawing still relied on additive logic, which involved adding overlapped information without associative relationships, heavily relying on the designer&amp;rsquo;s consistency. This additive logic persisted for a long time as it was considered stable for exploring and refining variations through traditional image media. However, this logic had limitations as it lacked connections between depicted elements and couldn&amp;rsquo;t incorporate physically relevant aspects that shape the generation of real-world forms. These limitations prompted architects to develop their design mindset.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
