<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reflection on Arman Wu&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://armanwu.github.io/categories/reflection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reflection on Arman Wu&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 19:28:58 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://armanwu.github.io/categories/reflection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Game Age Ratings: Protecting Children from Inappropriate Content</title>
      <link>https://armanwu.github.io/posts/2023/07/understanding-game-age-ratings-protecting-children-from-inappropriate-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 19:28:58 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://armanwu.github.io/posts/2023/07/understanding-game-age-ratings-protecting-children-from-inappropriate-content/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many parents are concerned about the types of games their children play. They worry that some games may not be suitable for their child’s age. However, what they often don’t realize is that every game actually comes with an age rating determined by the developer and publisher. These ratings are designed to guide parents in deciding whether a game is appropriate for their children.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every game developer and publisher has a target market in mind, and they pay close attention to this when setting an age rating. The rating is based on the game’s content—such as violence, strong language, or sexual themes. For example, a game that contains intense violence will be given a higher age rating than one that is more family-friendly. Parents should understand that these ratings are not just suggestions, but important guidelines to help them choose the right games for their children.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
