<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Architecture on Arman Wu&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://armanwu.github.io/categories/architecture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Architecture on Arman Wu&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 21:01:46 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://armanwu.github.io/categories/architecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Critiquing BIM in the Architecture World: Fostering Open-Mindedness for Advancement</title>
      <link>https://armanwu.github.io/architecture/critiquing_bim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 21:01:46 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://armanwu.github.io/architecture/critiquing_bim/</guid>
      <description>As an architect and BIM practitioner, I fully recognize the tremendous potential of Building Information Modeling (BIM) in improving the efficiency and quality of architectural projects. However, in order to ensure ongoing progress, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial for BIM practitioners not to turn a blind eye to any weaknesses that may still exist in this technology. In this article, I will explain why criticism of BIM is important and how having an open-minded approach to criticism can drive advancements in this technology within the architecture industry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Architecture, Computer, and Philosophy</title>
      <link>https://armanwu.github.io/architecture/arch_comp_phil/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 21:54:46 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://armanwu.github.io/architecture/arch_comp_phil/</guid>
      <description>In the ever-evolving world of architecture, the integration of philosophy and computer technology has emerged as a vital component in shaping the future of design. Architects are no longer solely focused on aesthetics and functionality; they are now exploring the profound intersections between architecture, philosophy, and computer science. This article delves into the significance of merging these three fields, highlighting how their interplay contributes to the creation of innovative and socially responsible architectural solutions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Techniques of Generative Design</title>
      <link>https://armanwu.github.io/architecture/gd_techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 22:01:46 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://armanwu.github.io/architecture/gd_techniques/</guid>
      <description>Generative design, as a powerful approach in architecture, encompasses a range of techniques that push the boundaries of creativity and innovation. By leveraging computational algorithms, generative design unlocks new possibilities and opens up uncharted territories in the realm of architectural exploration. Among the many techniques used in generative design, several prominent ones stand out, including cellular automata, genetic algorithms, shape grammar, and more.&#xA;Cellular automata, first introduced by mathematician John von Neumann and popularized by scientist Stephen Wolfram, provide a fascinating tool for generative design.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discovering Harmony in Architecture with Generative Design</title>
      <link>https://armanwu.github.io/architecture/generative_design/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 20:44:46 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://armanwu.github.io/architecture/generative_design/</guid>
      <description>In the complex world of architecture, generative design has emerged, opening doors to thousands of possibilities for harmonious and aesthetic designs. The collaboration between humans and computers gives rise to surprising solutions, unearthing new ideas with unlimited freedom.&#xA;Generative design involves the consideration of complex factors, including spatial layout, lighting, and energy efficiency. In this remarkable process, algorithms can be programmed to optimize designs based on specific criteria, creating unexpected harmony in the combination of variables.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Thinking in Architectural Design Process</title>
      <link>https://armanwu.github.io/architecture/computational_think/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 21:44:46 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://armanwu.github.io/architecture/computational_think/</guid>
      <description>The use of computers in the field of architectural design initially only involved digitizing tasks that were traditionally done manually. Computer-based modeling or drawing still relied on additive logic, which involved adding overlapped information without associative relationships, heavily relying on the designer&amp;rsquo;s consistency. This additive logic persisted for a long time as it was considered stable for exploring and refining variations through traditional image media. However, this logic had limitations as it lacked connections between depicted elements and couldn&amp;rsquo;t incorporate physically relevant aspects that shape the generation of real-world forms.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
